キルア失格の理由を聞いた ゴンの心は
Guts x And x Courage
ギタラクル…　いや
An intense dodgeball match has begun.
キルアの実の兄　イルミへの怒りに 満ちあふれていた
Gon was injured by Razor's throw, but his eyes burn with fire.
キルアに謝れ！
I'm going to use Back. But you're...
謝る？　何を？
He won't listen to us... Fine... However!
そんなことも分からないの？ うん。
Don't use Back until we're
down to two inside players!
お前に あにきの資格なんてないよ。
Got it? Now let's start.
兄弟に資格がいるのかな？
Gon, get patched up.
友達になるのだって 資格なんていらない！
All right, I'm good now.
こいつ…
I'm the type that tends to hold grudges.
もう謝らなくていいよ。
Time for payback, Razor!
そして　どうする？
Take this...
決まってんじゃん！ キルアを連れ戻す！
Black Goreinu!
まるで　キルが 誘拐でもされたような口ぶりだな。
So he can swap the black
one with other people? You got me good...
あいつは　自分の足で ここを出て行ったんだよ？
That's what you get. You're out of there!
でも　自分の意思じゃ　ない！ お前達に操られてるんだから 誘拐されたも同然だ！
He's out, but he's still able to return inside. At least we can force him to use up his Back.
ちょうど　そのことで 議論していたところじゃ　ゴン。
Huh?
クラピカとレオリオの両方から 異議が唱えられてな
What?
キルアの様子は 自称ギタラクルとの対戦中と
Goreinu! You have an interesting ability.
その後において 明らかに不自然だった。
You should use it wisely.
対戦の際に 何らかの暗示をかけられて
Hold on! What was that?!
あのような行為に至ったものと 考えられる。
There's no rule against passing
the ball to an opponent.
通常なら　いかに強力な催眠術でも 殺人を強いることは不可能だ！ しかし　殺し屋一家で育った キルアにとって
And you're allowed to hit
people in the face here.
殺人は日常のことで
So his attack was also legal.
倫理的抑制が働かなくても 不思議は　ない。
Had the ball touched the floor, I'd be out.
俺とボドロの対戦中に 事が起きたってことだ。
Once the user's unconscious,
the Nen beast disappears.
状況を見れば キルアが 俺の合格を助けたようにも見える。
As I suspected, his ability works with
his direct control, not automatically.
ならば　不合格になるのは キルアじゃなくて 俺のほうだろ？
If he regains consciousness, the black ape may begin inside the court.
いずれにせよ　キルアは当時
I don't anticipate that happening, though.
自らの意思で 行動できない状態にあった。 よって 彼の失格は　妥当ではない！
If the interior players are reduced
to zero before Goreinu wakes up, the match will be decided.
全て臆測にすぎんのう… 証拠は何もない。 明らかに　殺人を指示するような 言動があったわけではない。
It's impossible... Even if he comes to, he won't be in any condition to remake his Nen beast right away.
いや　それ以前に　まず 催眠をかけたとする根拠が怪しい。
Inside the court, it's three versus three.
レオリオとボドロの対戦直後に 事が起きたという点については
But we're obviously outmatched.
問題ないと思っておる。
Half our players are gone, and we only have one
injured kid on the outside.
２人の総合的な能力は あの時点では　ほぼ互角。 経験の差で ボドロを上位に置いたが
Our opponents have a solid outside team,
so they can attack from anywhere.
格闘能力のみをとれば
Razor is still inside,
without needing to use Back.
むしろ　レオリオのほうが有利と わしは見ておった。
And the ball rebounded to our opponents.
あえて　キルアが手助けをするような 場面では　なかったじゃろ。
We're at a clear disadvantage!
何？
Well, then...
ヒソカと戦ってた時の あんたの様子だ。
Who is up next?
お互いの余力がある状態で
Me? What do I do? It's impossible! I can't catch that!
あんたに何かを告げた ヒソカのほうが負けを宣言した。
I have to dodge! It made a sharp turn?
ささやかれたほうが 負けを認めるのは分かる。
Hisoka!
何らかの圧力を かけられたんだろうな。
Bungee Gum!
不自然が理由で 合否に異論があると言うなら
That bastard... He got us good.
あんたの合格も 相当　不自然だぜ？
He faked going for me, when his real goal was taking out
Bisky and Hisoka in a straight line.
後ろ暗いことがないなら あの時　何を言われたか
Actually, he could have
教えてもらおう！ 答える義務は　ない。
gambled that I'd dodge left.
義務は　なくても 責任は　あると思うぜ？
Had I done that...
ないな。
Bisky is out!
私の合格が不自然なら
Move to the outside court.
不戦勝での合格も 自然とは　いえないな。
What? Didn't she dodge? My own fault.
何!?
Huh?
どうだっていいんだ。
Yes.
おいおい
I was certain she'd dodged it...
俺は　さっさと講習だけ済ませて 帰りてぇんだがな。
We're down to two! You can't let them get the ball!
お前な！
Back!
どうだっていいんだ！ そんなこと！
Gon has used Back.
ひとの合格に とやかく言うことなんて　ない。
Can we really trust a kid with this?
自分の合格に不満なら 満足できるまで精進すればいい。
He's no ordinary kid...
キルアなら　もう一度 ハンター試験を受ければ
He's the only one who's even
tried to catch Razor's throw.
絶対　合格できる。
Are you all right?
今回　落ちたことは 残念だけど仕方がない。
Yeah. Listen to me. Do not overdo it!
もしも今まで 望んでいないキルアに
What's one plus one? Yeah.
無理やり 人殺しをさせていたなら…。
This is hopeless. Okay!
お前を許さない！
Beat him, even if it kills you!
許さないか…　で　どうする？
You okay? Yep. I've discovered something.
どうもしないさ。 お前達から　キルアを取り戻して 会わせないようにするだけだ！
If the ball travels outside the court,
it becomes much less powerful. Without using Ko, I only injured a couple fingers.
オホン。
Don't be stupid...
さて諸君　よろしいかな？ ゴンの言った通り
If we can't win no matter what
we do, all this is pointless!
自分の「本当の合格」は 自分自身で決めればよい。
You'd better cool down, stupid. Aren't you mad? Huh?!
また　他人の合否を うんぬん言っても
If you'd dodged left, you could've died.
我々は　決定を覆すつもりは　ない。
Right?
おぬし達の合格も　また変わらぬ。
I'm really pissed off...
え　それでは 説明会を再開いたします。
We have to utterly destroy him!
皆さんに　お渡しした このカードが
You must have a plan in mind... Yeah.
ハンターライセンスです。
I've got this.
このカードがあれば 民間人が 入国禁止の国の約９０％と
Killua, stand over there.
立ち入り禁止区域の７５％まで 入ることが可能になります。 すげぇ。
Plant yourself firmly, and hold the ball.
さらに　公的施設の９５％は タダで使用でき 銀行からの融資も 一流企業並みに受けられます。
I get it!
売れば　人生７回ぐらい 遊んで過ごせますし
First comes rock!
持っているだけでも 一生　遊んで暮らせるはずです。
His aura just spiked!
それだけに　紛失　盗難には 十分　気をつけてください。 再発行は　いたしません。
Rock, paper...
我々の統計では ハンターに合格した者の ５人に１人が　１年以内に
Rock!
「カードを守ること」と いっていいでしょう。 あとは　あなた方次第です。
First comes rock!
試練を乗り越え　自分の力を信じて 夢に向かって前進してください。
His aura just spiked!
では　ここにいる７名を 新しくハンターとして認定する！
Rock, paper...
キルアの居場所を教えてもらう！
Number 13 is out.
本当に連れ戻す気？ やめたほうがいいと思うよ。
Catching the ball while touching the area
outside is illegal and does not count.
誰が　やめるもんか！ キルアは俺の友達だ！
Play will resume with Team Gon's
outside players controlling the ball.
絶対に連れ戻す！
Wow!
後ろの２人も同じかい？
He sent the biggest one flying. Damn it...
当然よ！
That wasn't good enough!
うん。
He looks unhappy...
He's actually upset.
いいだろう。
That kid's really got guts.
教えたところで どうせ　たどり着けないし。
Not enough yet...
キルは自宅に戻ってるはずだ。 自宅？
Not enough to defeat the real Razor!
ククルーマウンテン。
I need more power!
ククルーマウンテン？ 分かった　ありがとう。
Okay, let's do it again.
いいのかい？　殺し屋が 自分のアジト教えちゃって。 うん　別に隠してないし 地元じゃ有名だしね。
Give it to Razor good! Yeah.
まっ　彼らも 行ってみれば分かるよ。 俺達と彼らじゃ 住む世界が違うってことがね。 ん？
To beat Razor, I'll need a lot more power.
できれば　今のうちに…
Ren.
ゴンは　僕の獲物だ。
What?
手出ししたら ただじゃおかないよ。
His aura is immense.
分かってるよ　短い付き合いだが ヒソカの好みは把握した。
You may have chosen the wrong sport. He has all the time in the
world to build up his power.
で　ヒソカ 君は　これから　どうするんだ？
You might want to dodge this one.
じっと待つよ。
You must be joking.
果実が　おいしく実るまで。
into my fist.
ククルーマウンテンか 聞いたことないな。
First comes rock!
あ　いや…　分からないな。 後で　ネットで調べてみよう。
Take this, Razor!
ん？ ん？
Rock!
よう！
Paper...
あっ　ハンゾーさん！ 俺は　国に戻る。
Rock!
もし　俺の国に来ることがあったら 言ってくれ。
Perfect! No way he'll catch that!
じゃあね！ ん？
He's receiving it?
さっきは　感情的になって すまなかった。
He used his own body to reduce its power.
いや　私のほうこそ 非礼を詫びよう。
Nice move. That required perfect timing.
いや　あんたが正しいからこそ 俺も　むきになったんだ。
But he was able to pull it off.
不戦勝での不満を　あの場で ぶちまけたかったんだと思う。
This man truly is strong.
問題は　これから何をするか だからな。 ああ　その通りだ。
Amazing...
俺は　これから世界を回って いろんな情報を集めて
You can do more than just
dodge or catch the ball.
さまざまな未確認生物を 見つけ出す
But I doubt that tip will help you.
幻獣ハンターになる。 幻獣ハンターか。 ねぇねぇ　それ何？
That ball was as strong as Razor's, but it didn't even reach the ceiling.
あっ　これか？ これで　いろいろと 情報を仕入れるのさ。
He managed to burn off enough
momentum with that receive.
何か知りたい情報があるか？ すぐ調べられるぜ。
Now the ball's directly over him!
じゃあ　「ジン」って名前の ハンターを調べてくれる？
Bungee gum.
ジン＝フリークス！
Too bad for you. You have to catch the ball, after all.
サトツ？
Back.
おいおい そのジンってハンターは
Razor has used Back!
一体　何者なんだ？ え？
He remains inside.
厳重なセキュリティーシステムと アクセス制限が　かけられてて
Both teams have used Back,
and it's three-on-two!
一切の情報が シャットアウトされてる。
The tables have turned!
こいつ 国家レベルの重要人物だぜ。
Really? Our team is the one on the ropes.
あっ　そうなの？　じゃあ　いいや。
Hisoka probably isn't in any shape to throw.
お前の親父　予想以上に とんでもねえ人物みたいだな。 アハハ…。
No, he probably can't even hold
the ball with his right hand.
そっか　じゃあ　また何かあったら 連絡してくれ。
Gon's attacks used immense amounts of aura.
これが　俺のメルアドだ。 じゃあな！
He should be starting to feel tired about now.
じゃあね！ あっ！ え？ ククルーマウンテンのことも 調べてもらえばよかったな。
For him to be able to make another,
equally strong throw is unlikely.
確かに。
So Killua is the only uninjured
player left on the inside?
いや　ネテロ会長も言っていたが もう私達は　ハンター同士だ。
No, you have it backwards.
行動を　むやみに 他のハンターに知られるのは 好ましくないだろう 自分達で調べるとしよう。
He's probably sustained the most damage of all. What do you mean?
サトツさん！
Yeah, but we need one more... I think.
ゴンくん　お忘れですよ。
I'll put everything into this one. All right!
あっ　そっか　ありがとう！
This time, end it.
それと　ちょっと　いいですか？
One more throw... I can take it.
ん？
Just hold out!
では　先にロビーに行ってるぞ。 うん！
When Gon launched his ball, Killua barely used any
protective Nen on his hands.
失礼ながら　今し方の会話が 聞こえてしまいまして。
That's insane. You saw the power of that launch... Like a cannon opening fire!
実は　私　主に遺跡の発掘と修復 保護を　なりわいにしています。
Correct. Essentially, he used his bare hands
to form the cannon's barrel.
以前は名誉を求め　発掘のみに 心血を注いでいましたが あるハンターの仕事を見て そんな自分が 恥ずかしくなりましてね。
Had Killua used a significant amount
of Nen to protect his hands, his aura would have become a
barrier against Gon's punch, reducing the power to the ball.
そのハンターは 発掘しただけでなく その後も私財を使って 完璧な修復を行い
In order to avoid weakening the ball, Killua used hardly any aura on his hands.
将来的な遺跡の保護を 考慮に入れた上で
Killua's hands must be in far worse shape
一般の人々も 見ることができるような
than Hisoka's right hand.
環境整備を施したのです。 私は　遺跡の美しさよりも
Damn... I'm a fool! How could I not be over there?
その作業工程を思い 打ちのめされました。
I know the technique.
現在では そのハンターが行った仕事が
And I can do it faster than Killua.
遺跡管理のマニュアルとして 世界に 取り入れられているほどです。 そして　そのハンターが ゴンくん
In the instant before Gon touches the ball, you can apply a lightning-fast coat of
aura to your hands for protection! Wait!
先程　あなたが尋ねていた ジン＝フリークスその人なのです。
Time out! Ref, I have a question. What is it?
私も 一度　お会いしてみたいと思い 彼のことを いろいろ調べてみました。
Can inside players choose
to move to the outside? That doesn't violate any rules, but you can't return inside.
ですが　ひと言で言えば謎です。
Right... Come here!
彼自身のことは 全く分かりませんでした。 そうなんだ　やっぱり。
Gon, if you come outside,
I can hold the ball for you.
彼は 私の手本とするハンターです。
Killua's hands must be ravaged by now.
一度　お会いして 礼を言うのが　私の夢です。
I doubt he's in any condition
to hold the ball for you.
うん！
I know how to apply a lightning-fast coat of aura
話は　それだけです。
in order to protect my hands.
わざわざ呼び止めて すみませんでした。 ううん　いろいろ　ありがとう サトツさん。
I'll hold the ball, and you can
take Razor out from here.
それじゃ！ あぁ　ゴンくん。
It's our only way to win. We can't do that. Yeah.
ん？
Wh-Why not?
あぁ　いや… お体に　お気をつけて。
Where's the problem? It would be a cop-out. Huh?
うん！　サトツさんも！
This isn't the time to worry about that!
じゃあね！
Don't overdo it, pops.
まずは　ククルーマウンテンを 調べてみようぜ。
Then show me your hands.
ああ。
I'm all right.
パドキア共和国？　知らねえな どの辺の国だ？
Look! He can't feel anything but pain.
ちょっと待て 今　地図に切り替える。
I can do this! I can take one more ball.
ここが　パドキア共和国だ。
Gon, I can do this! It's impossible!
大丈夫　情勢は安定してる。
Gon, help me convince him.
一般観光客でも行ける国だ。
I already knew...
そこに　キルアが？ 飛行船で３日といったところか 出発は　いつにする？
I knew Killua's hands were messed up.
今日！　今すぐ！ ああ　異議なしだ！
Tsezgerra-san, I'm sorry, but I won't move outside.
分かった 早速　チケットを予約しよう。
I need Killua to hold the ball.
何だよ ちっとも進まねえじゃねぇか。
If Bisky or Hisoka held it,
I probably couldn't use my full strength.
マズいな　これでは 飛行船の時間に間に合わない。 おっちゃん どうにかしてくれよ！
The only reason I can focus
wholly on hitting the ball
…っていっても 渋滞ですからね　ここ一本道だし。
is because Killua's holding it for me.
おい　ゴン！　空港まで どれくらいあると思ってんだよ！ 俺　１分でも１秒でも早く キルアを連れ戻したいんだ！
We will now resume the match. Honestly, I'm not too good at throwing!
フフっ。 ったく！　しょうがねえな！
Now we're even.
フフっ　こうして走っていると ハンター試験を思い出すな。
Brilliant! She hit him at just the right angle
so the ball would rebound to us.
こんなのハンター試験に比べたら 屁でもないよ！
Number 2 is out! That leaves only...
違いねえ！
Razor alone!
よし！　空港まで競走だ！
Gon, we need to regain
the ball from Razor first. Of course.
よい
One sec.
かくしてゴン達は パドキア共和国へと向かった
I understand. That sounds interesting.
キルアの自宅があるという ククルーマウンテンを目指して
I'm not sure it'll work, though... Oh, but I would so love to try it.
サトツ。 メンチ　ブハラ。
Man, you always come up
with the craziest ideas.
ねぇ　サトツ さっき　ヤバかったでしょ？
Counting on you, Killua.
フフっ　見てたんですか。
We will resume the match now.
不思議な子ですねぇ つい　肩を持ちたくなりますよ。
Gon and Killua share a strong bond of trust.
うっかり　喋るところでした。
What sort of team play will emerge
本当のハンター試験は まだ終わってないことを。
when their friendship is backed
by the addition of Hisoka?